<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd"><dita><CoverTitle id="id1617M0U0WLJ" class="- topic/topic "><CTitle id="id184NG80E0RO" class="- topic/title ">Federal Acquisition Regulation</CTitle><CBody id="id184NG80I0E9" class="- topic/body "><CoverIssued id="id184NG80N04Y" class="- topic/p ">Issued March2005 by the:</CoverIssued><CoverGSADODNASA id="id184NG9004XW" class="- topic/p ">GENERAL SERVICES ADMINISTRATION DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE NATIONAL AERONAUTICS AND SPACE ADMINISTRATION</CoverGSADODNASA><CoverEdition id="id184NG9008QN" class="- topic/p ">(This edition includes the consolidation of all Federal Acquisition Circulars through 2001-27)</CoverEdition><CoverTitle48 id="id184NG900DBI" class="- topic/p ">TITLE 48-FEDERAL ACQUISITION REGULATIONS SYSTEM</CoverTitle48><CoverChapterTitle id="id184NG900JBI" class="- topic/p ">Chapter1</CoverChapterTitle><CoverFARTitle id="id184NG900OX4" class="- topic/p ">Federal Acquisition Regulation</CoverFARTitle><CoverVolumeCtr id="id184NG900TZJ" class="- topic/p ">VolumeII</CoverVolumeCtr><ForewordTitle id="id184NG900Y7U" class="- topic/p ">Foreword</ForewordTitle><ForewordBody id="id184NG9020BF" class="- topic/p ">This March2005 edition is a complete reissue of the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR). It includes all Federal Acquisition Circulars through 2001-27. The effective date of the overall FAR remains April1,1984.</ForewordBody><ForewordBody id="id184NG90702L" class="- topic/p ">The FAR is the primary regulation for use by all Federal Executive agencies in their acquisition of supplies and services with appropriated funds. It became effective on April1,1984, and is issued within applicable laws under the joint authorities of the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of Defense, and the Administrator for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, under the broad policy guidelines of the Administrator, Office of Federal Procurement Policy, Office of Management and Budget.</ForewordBody><ForewordBody id="id184NG90B0XK" class="- topic/p ">The FAR precludes agency acquisition regulations that unnecessarily repeat, paraphrase, or otherwise restate the FAR, limits agency acquisition regulations to those necessary to implement FAR policies and procedures within an agency, and provides for coordination, simplicity, and uniformity in the Federal acquisition process. It also provides for agency and public participation in developing the FAR and agency acquisition regulations.</ForewordBody></CBody></CoverTitle></dita>